Gulbala Salamov



github.com/gulbalasalamov linkedin.com/in/gulbalasalamov



<u>g.salamov@gmail.com</u> +905367102202



Turkey, Azerbaijan



20.11.1990



Completed



About me: I am a Researcher & Developer from reputable universities with a strong motivation to succeed in the industry and academy. I have improved skills in problem identification and implementation of effective solutions. I have good interpersonal communication and social skills.

My career objectives: I'd like to invest in myself further with top skills modern engineers need to succeed. By far I have 3 years experience in agile software engineering practices from conception to completion and 1 year active professional programming experience. Recently my focus shifts into best practices applied in the industry and thus I am happy to develop & implement new solutions integrating applications across enterprise or its units

Work Experience 1

Senior Researcher & Jr. Software Developer 04.2019 - 06.2020 (Full Time)

ExCiteS Research Group University College London, U.K.

Develop:

- · Maintained Android data collection app, Sapelli, written in Java
- · Successfully added new features and fixed the existing issues in Sapelli
- Build new Sapelli Visualiser mobile app to display collected meaningful data
- Set up Virtual Server on cloud services to use <u>GeoKey</u> REST Api ready backend infrastructure solution to create projects, manage access, store and validate data
- Picked up existing code base, wrote well-documented and maintainable code and developed it further using GitHub as a source code management repository.
- Assisted with other technical expertise as required within the scope of project

Design:

- Designed and implemented mobile app prototypes for <u>ECSAnVis</u> €2.5M project funded by European Research Council (ERC)
- · Identified key user groups and created in-depth user scenarios
- Determined the information architecture of a digital product
- Created high fidelity representation of a design using Adobe XD
- Improved user experience by regular UI/UX meetings and testing the mockup

Research:

Contributed to academic research, presentations and workshops

Researcher & Software Developer Intern 06.2017 - 09.2017 (Internship)

Rzayev Research Group
State University of New York at Buffalo. USA

- Built interactive prototypes for university mobile app
- Collaborated closely with university IT department and project teams to conduct user research
- Created technical documentations for future development references
- · Maintained IT support of Labs

Software Development Specialist & Technology Consultant 01.2013 - 09.2016 (Freelance)

S.I.P Azerbaijan

- Communicated with clients and verified their needs by reports
- Simplified complex technical concepts by high quality prototypes, use cases and diagrams
- Prepared requirement analysis and wrote technical specifications
- · Contributed to the software design and architecture
- Built e-commerce web sites using open source CMS (Wordpress & Moodle)

Teaching Experience ²

02.2014 - 06.2014 (Internship) ICT Teacher

METU Foundation Schools
Turkey

- Lectured students about real programming languages and built simple apps using Java and visual coding tools
- Instructed students to build algorithms for real life problems by playing logic based games
- Administrated LMS (Moodle), created courses, exams and assignments
- Prepared digital learning materials including video, documents and posters

09.2013 - 02.2014 (Internship) ICT Teacher

Private Ari Schools Turkey

- · Lectured under guidance for teaching practice
- Made plans and presentations for teaching
- · Adjusted classroom conditions for appropriate teaching environment
- Observed authentic teaching and different aspect of the teaching profession

Education ³

Hacettepe University, Turkey. PhD in Geomatics Engineering	2018 -
Swansea University, U.K. MSc in Computer Science	2014 - 2016
Middle East Technical University, Turkey BSc in Computer Education & Instructional Technology	2010 - 2014

Skills & Competenecies ⁴

" * " indicates familiarity with the concept but **limited** experience.

A. Programming Languages		
Languages	Java (7 ,8, 11) , Android	
Java Core	 Data Structures (<i>List, Maps, Generics, Collections</i>) Exceptions, Interfaces, Working with files and data 	
Code Organization	 Object Oriented Programming Functional Programming * Functions, Functional Streams , Lambda Exp, Optional Design Patterns Singleton, Strategy, Decorator, Factory 	
Version CS	Git, GitHub	
Build Tools	Gradle, Maven	
Testing Framework	Debugging, JUnit 5 *	

B. Server Side Technology Stack		
Language	Java	
Framework	Spring	
Spring Framework Core	 Configuration Spring MVC Dependency Injection * 	
Spring Security	 JSON Web Token (JWT) * Form Auth * Basic Auth * Authentication and Authorization * 	
Spring Boot Databases	Spring Data JPA *, PostgreSQL, SQL, MySql *	

C. Front End Technology Stack		
Language	HTML, CSS	
Framework	Angular *	
Prototype	Adobe XD, Photoshop, <i>Figma</i> *	

D. Low-Code & No-Code Technology	
Platform	OutSystems *

E. Other Skills	
Additional Tools	Jira, Trello, Slack, Microsoft Teams
Soft Skills	Communication, Patience, Open Minded, Time Management
Useful Skills	OS (Windows & Linux), Office Apps, R & D, Academic writings

Books 5

Android Sanatı - Android Mobile Programming Book

(Gulbala Salamov¹, Volkan Gurbuz²) LEVEL Publishing House, Turkey (2017) ISBN 6058352766

https://www.kitapyurdu.com/kitap/android-sanati/434078.html

Publications 6

A Novel Portable Nanotechnology Approach for Targeted Cancer Therapy

2nd International Symposium on Multidisciplinary Studies Innovative Technologies (2018) Authors: Bunyatova, U., Kocum C., Haberal E., Asadullayev A., Salamov G. https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8567302

Technology of modelling of integrity and fuzzy model of knowledge - IFMK

2nd International Symposium on Multidisciplinary Studies Innovative Technologies (2018) Authors: Bunyatova, F. K., Salamov G.

https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8566690

New Strategy of Distance Education

Universal Journal of Educational Research, Horizon Research Publishing, USA (2014)

Authors: Bunyatova, F., Salamov, G.

http://www.hrpub.org/journals/article_info.php?aid=1578

Simulation Learning Based on Formal-Logical and Fuzzy Logics

6th International Computer and Instructional Technologies Symposium, Turkey (2012)

Authors: Bunyatova, F., Salamov, G.

https://www.pegem.net/Akademi/kongre_detay.aspx?id=137107

Logic of Integrity, Fuzzy Logic and Knowledge Modelling For Machine Education

5th International Conference on Application of ICT, Azerbaijan (2011)

Authors: Bunyatova, F., Salamov, G.

https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/6110956

Professional Memberships 7

European Cooperation in Science and Technology (COST) (11.2018 – Present)

- COST CA15212 Citizen Science Work Group Member
 - WG2 Develop synergies with education
 - WG4 Enhance the role of CS for civil society

https://cs-eu.net/users/gulbalasalamov

Volunter Work 8

METU Society Science Center (02.2014 – 06.2014)

- · Presentation of scientific and technological devices to students
- Photo and video recording during demonstrations

Certificates 9

- Training School on Digital Transformations in Citizen Science & Social Innovation (ITALY, 2019)
- International Student Festival of HARKAT (IRAN, 2018)
- National Computer & Instructional Technologies Congress, (TURKEY, 2013)
- Innovative Teachers Forum (TURKEY, 2012)
- International Computer & Instructional Technologies Sympusium (TURKEY, 2012)
- Application of Information & Communication Technologies (AZERBAIJAN, 2011)
- International Educational Technology Conference (TURKEY, 2009)

Interests 10

Photography, Sports, Cooking, Research, Teaching

Languages 11

- 1. Azerbaijani (Native)
- 2. Turkish (Excellent)
- 3. English (Excellent) IELTS: 6.5 (July 2018)
- 4. Russian (Good)
- 5. German (Basic)